Yep you read that, right today we
are traveling to Argentina to talk
about all the glorious Dulce de Leche
and other sweet treats that they have
available over there so let's go
see what it's all [Music] about.
This is an exciting video for me because I started
talking to the owner of this business years ago
and they were one of the first supporters of the
channel and we've become pretty good friends since
then, and I'm really excited to say that they
have opened their own ice cream shop which is
amazing. It is in Vera Cruz in Mexico I'm going to
put a nice little map on the screen and pinpoint
exactly where it is so you can head over there and
try some of their glorious Argentinian gelato. Now
before we dive deep into this I wanted to point
out that this is a new service that Polar Ice
Creamery is offering, if you want me to advertise
your ice cream, scoop shop, van, whatever it is,
even your just your brand, then head over to
www.polaricecreamery.com click on the contact us
page and let's discuss what it is you need, but
for now, this video is all about Gellö Helado.
So first things first, let's
talk about the name Gellö Helado,
Gello is a combination word of gelato, which
obviously is Italian for ice cream and hello
so that gives us Gellö. Then Helado is (silent H
if you don't speak Spanish) I don't have to ask,
um that is ice cream that's what that means
so we've got a nice little combination and
one of the big things in Argentina is Dulce
de Leche, it's very different to the DDL you
buy in North America and in the UK. What the UK
do is so incredibly cloyingly sweet it kind of
overtakes lots of other flavors and when I started
talking to my friend Natalia it was let's look at
one of these recipes let's take one of your
classic Argentinian recipes and make it here,
you know there's a couple of things I've
had to change because I just couldn't get
one of the ingredients but what I did is
I went online to this amazing website,
and bought a good supply of different DDL.
Now this one is one of the ones that they
use but they also use another one so there's
two different types that they use they use
this repostero and patereo one is specifically
designed for use in ice cream it's got a very
different flavor profile ,well not profile it's
just a very different strength flavor and then
this one which is a bit more you know in tune
with putting on cookies and bread and all the
other things that they they use this for.
So I've laid out these because this was a
wonderful gift from my friend these turned up
the other day so I'm going to open these up in
another video because I think that's worthy
of a whole video unto itself. So if you're
interested in that, like and subscribe,
follow along and we're going to do this
for lots of countries and lots of ice cream
companies around the world in the near future.
So let's just move these out the way & back
to the ice cream. So I got the base recipe
from them and made a couple of adjustments to
make it a bit easier for you guys to make in
your ice cream machines at home because
that's really what this is all about.
So today we are going to make Gello
Helados Argentinian Dulce de Leche gelato.
So there's no milk in this recipe, we're
going to start with our water 471g of water
(cup measurements in the description) and
on the screen as well, and in here we've
got our skimmed milk powder which is 60g, in this
container we have our 28g of whole milk powder,
we have 60g of dextrose (powdered glucose if
you can't find dextrose) and we also have our
stabilizer and emulsifier combination we're
going to give that a quick stir because we're
going to drop in our 150g of 33% whipping cream.
Finally in goes our 126g of Havana dulce de leche
and 90g of Vacalin dulce de leche and now we're
going to get that on the hob and heat it up.
Now I've used caragennan and Locust bean gum
and guar gum in here along with sunflower
lecithin for the emulsifier and because of those
ingredients, we're going to need to bring this up
to 85° centigrade and keep it there for a couple
of minutes just to make sure it's fully hydrated.
Once it's up to that temperature and really
nicely emulsified, a really nice homogenized mix,
we're going to take it off the heat put it
in a container and get it in the fridge.
Now the following day after chilling overnight,
you can leave it for about 4 hours if you want
take it out of the fridge, give it a nice
good stir, pop in your machine look at
that churn..... absolutely glorious. When it's
ready and down to about - 10 - 12°C take it out,
put it in your ice cream containers, then
in the fridge...nope...then in the freezer.
The ice cream's been in the freezer for 24 hours,
going to take it out and get some scooped up
into a bowl.... the smell that comes out of
this container is incredible so let's
see how well it scoops.... straight in
no major issues look how creamy that is
that is delicious can't wait to eat this.
A nice little zoom in shot for you you can see how
creamy this actually is it's really high quality
ice cream this much much better than you're
going to ever buy in the stores I promise you.
So it's the next day scoop some of this
up as you can see it scoops beautifully,
it's straight out the freezer it's got a
enough invert sugar in there due to the
process of making dulche de leche so
it scoops really nicely straight out
the freezer which means you don't have to
wait for 5 or 10 minutes, you know how much
I hate doing that. So let's just try some
before we talk about it some [Music] more.
Perfect texture, no discernable large ice crystals
in there super super smooth really really nice
dulce de leche flavor. Now something to note about
South American DDL is it's nowhere near as sweet
as the stuff you buy in the stores here, you know
you can buy Eagle brand DDL in a can, it's just
not the same it's way way too sweet compared to
this stuff. Now these three, also got two more of
those, they came from the www.theargentino.com and
that's just a small business based in Patagonia in
Argentina that ship out I think, all over the
world, and shipping was really really good so
I got all these three really well priced nicely
shipped nicely packed definitely recommend it
if you want to get something from that part of
the world. But what we've got here is a slightly
modified version of Gello Helados recipe for DDL
Gelato and this kind of recipe is designed for
add-ins as well so they're primed for things
like nuts and chocolate addins. It's a very
popular kind of ice cream base in Argentina and
for those people that are in Vera Cruz of Mexico,
you are in for a treat if you head over and
try this which I strongly recommend you do.
So I hope you enjoyed this
quick visit to South America,
the glorious dulce de leche here and turned into
an absolute amazing gelato thanks for much for
watching don't forget to like And subscribe
and we'll see you on the next [Music] video.